

160 S Fl Molino Ave. Pasadena, CA, USA

🛘 (626)-365-9803 | 🔀 dpastorm@caltech.edu | 😭 danielpastor.me | 📮 PastorD | 🛅 dpastorm

Summary

Broad experience in applying estimation and control techniques for robotic applications, covering algorithm development, software implementation and hardware prototyping. My current interest is efficient control techniques using modern learning methods. Currently finishing a PhD at Caltech, estimated graduation June 2020.

Education

California Institute of Technology

Pasadena, USA

DOCTOR OF PHILOSOPHY IN SPACE ENGINEERING Sept. 2015 - PRESENT

- Thesis: Learning Aerodynamic Interactions for Quadrotors, advisor: Joel Burdick
- Development of Data-Driven Spectral Methods for dynamics systems, applied to multirotor landing
- Development of miniature pressure-sensor array to enhance multirotor control algorithms

Cranfield University Cranfield, UK

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN AUTONOMOUS VEHICLE DYNAMICS & CONTROL

Sept. 2013 - Aug. 2014

- Master Thesis: Visual Odometry in Hardware. Analysis of the performance of computer vision techniques for very agile platforms. Development of new SLAM framework called OFLAAM, presented at ICUAS'15
- Group Project: Flight Tests using BAE Jetstream 31

Universidad Politécnica de Madrid (UPM)

Madrid, Spain

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE IN AEROSPACE ENGINEERING

Sept. 2008 - Aug. 2014

• Group Project: Low-orbit satellite control using gravity gradient

Research Experience __

Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL)

Pasadena, USA

July 2015 - PRESENT

AFFILIATE

- Heterogeneous Sensor Fusion via Confidence-rich 3D Grid Mapping for the Subterranean (SubT) Challenge
- · Design of a Ballistically-Launched Foldable Multirotor
- Verification of open-source Visual Inertial algorithms for Mars Helicopter mission

Space Dynamics Group, UPM

Madrid, Spain

GNC ENGINEER

Sept. 2014 - Aug. 2015

· Analysis of the navigation and control techniques for contact-less space debris removal mission LEOSWEEP

Tokyo Tech Institute of Technology, Okuma Laboratory

Tokyo, Japan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER TRAINEE

June. 2013 - Aug. 2013

- Development of a simulation model for gossamer structures (solar sails with booms and membranes)
- · Upgrade existing solar sail model to handle generic meshes for easy layout modification

Applied Physics Department at ETSIA, UPM

Madrid, Spain

SOFTWARE ENGINEER TRAINEE

Feb. 2013 - May. 2013

- Computer parallelization of plasma dynamics of Langmuir probe model with orbital speed
- Co-author of the patented software patented program "Kilaps" (Kinetic Langmuir Probe Software)

CONTROL ENGINEER TRAINEE

GMV

Intelliglass

Tres Cantos, Spain July. 2012 - August. 2012

Development of the translational control model of ESA mission Lunar Lander using Robust Control techniques

Madrid, Spain Nov. 2011 - May. 2012

SOFTWARE ENGINEER TRAINEE

- Development of thermal simulator in buildings with active windows
- · Integration of the window module into the rest of building simulation framework

NOVEMBER 22, 2019 DANIEL PASTOR

Skills

Programming Python for hardware implementation using ROS and machine learning packages, C/C++ during Tokyo Tech internship, Fortran 2003

during Plasma Physics and Intelliglass internships, Matlab for quick prototyping

Languages English, Spanish

Other Skills Document writing using Latex, mechanical design using Solid Works, version control using GIT, PCB design using Eagle, interactive

applications using Unity3D

Honors & Awards

2017 Caltech Space Challenge 2017, to design a Lunar Port concept with 32 participants

2014 La Caixa Fellowship, to study postgraduate studies in the US

2014 Sir Arthur Clarke Award 2014, with the team Cranspace for *Inspiration Mars* competition

2011 Optimula contest 2nd Place, by ETSII-UPM

2008 Silver Medal, XIX Spanish National Physics Olympiad

2008 **Scholarship Aula de Verano**, by UIMP (Universidad Internacional Menéndez Pelayo).

Selected Publications

- Carl Folkestad*, Daniel Pastor*, and Joel Burdick "Extended Dynamic Mode Decomposition with Learned Koopman Eigenfunctions for Prediction and Control", submitted to ICRA 2020
- Carl Folkestad*, Daniel Pastor*, Igor Mezic, Ryan Mohr, Maria Fonoberova, and Joel Burdick "Episodic Koopman Learning of Nonlinear Robot Dynamics with Application to Fast Quadrotor Landing", submitted to ACC 2020
- Amanda Bouman, Paul Nadan, Matthew Anderson, Daniel Pastor, Jacob Izraelevitz, Joel Burdick, and Brett Kennedy,
 "Design and Autonomous Stabilization of a Ballistically Launched Multirotor", submitted to ICRA 2020
- Daniel Pastor, Jacob Izraelevitz, Paul Nadan, Amanda Bouman, Joel Burdick, and Brett Kennedy, "Design of a Ballistically-Launched Foldable Multirotor", International Conference on Intelligent Robots and Systems (IROS) 2019, Macao
- Daniel Pastor*, Eric Heiden*, Pradyumna Vyshnav, Aliakbar Aghamohammadi, "Heterogeneous Sensor Fusion via Confidence-rich 3D Grid Mapping: Application to Physical Robots", International Conference of Experimental robotics (ISER) 2018, Buenos Aires
- Daniel Pastor, Hyo S. Shin "Optical Flow Localization And Appearance Mapping (OFLAAM) For Long-term Navigation", ICUAS'15, Denver
- Gonzalo Sanchez-Arriaga, Daniel Pastor, "Direct Vlasov Simulations of Electron Attracting Cylindrical Langmuir Probes in Flowing Plasmas" Physics of Plasmas, 2014, vol. 21, no 7 073504